The way you will approach the videos is through participatory attention, in which you allow yourself to become completely absorbed in the imagery and sounds, as if they are a part of you.
This is akin to becoming immersed or entering a state of flow.
First, you will guide you through this as a practice, and then you will apply this participatory approach while watching the erotic video.
During the actual experiment, you will simply be reminded to use this approach, so please give your full attention to these instructions now.
As you watch the video, open yourself to fully experience the unfolding imagery and sounds, not as something happening to you, but as something you are engaging with.
Allow yourself to become immersed.
Let the imagery and sound draw you inward, as a participant within the experience.
Let go of the idea that you are watching a video.
Instead, imagine you are inside it, experiencing it.
with your whole being, as if what's happening on screen is unfolding with and through you.
Let go of evaluation and instead sink into the moment.
Let your attention be guided inward by the experience itself.
allowing each image, sound, and movement to meet you as you are, enter a shared rhythm with what you see and hear, as if you and the video are part of the same living experience.
Tune into the texture of each moment, fully in your body, in the space where experience and awareness meet.
Allow yourself to become fully absorbed, participating completely.
Notice how the scenes invite your body to respond.
Tune into those responses.
Perhaps the shift in your breath, a wave of warmth, or a growing intensity.
You might feel tingling in your genitals, pulses in your vulva, or energy moving across your body.
Stay with each sensation, however small, writing them as ocean waves.
There's no right way to feel.
Your only task is to stay present and allow what arises to carry you.
Let yourself be in dialogue with these sensations.
Follow the waves as they emerge, intensify and dissolve.
This is not about controlling your experience, but about being in relationship with it, allowing, responding, and writing it like a current.
There is nothing to fix or manage.
You are simply present, letting the experience move through you.
Notice any sensations of arousal without judgment, and allow them to emerge naturally.
Just stay with it, not directing or evaluating, only connected to what is happening now.
You are an active participant in the moment.
Let the video draw you in and call forth responses already within you.
Become so deeply engaged, so absorbed that your awareness is carried by the rhythm of what's unfolding.
The more you engage this way, the more you settle into that flow.
Where you and the moment are not separate.
You're not pushing or trying, you're allowing.
Let distractions fade and self-consciousness soften, as your attention narrows into the unfolding experience.
This is merging.
Feel when you drop into that space and stay there.
Let your attention move fluidly between image, sound, and sensation, noticing how one informs the other, like dancing with a partner, you would tune, adjust, and respond, letting the interaction guide you.
The more you attune, the more naturally your awareness will sink with the unfolding moment.
Stay with the moment to moment unfolding.
Let your awareness sharpen through the pull of the experience itself.
Let yourself become captivated.
Allow each new sensation, to draw you deeper into the present, as if nothing else exists beyond what's unfolding.
As your attention deepens.
Let yourself merge with the flow of the moment.
Perhaps your sense of time shifts, or your mind quiets as you become more immersed.
Let self consciousness dissolve as you rest in embodied presence.
If thoughts arise, gently return to the vivid immediacy of what you're experiencing.
This moment, this pulse, this wave, this scene. Let yourself become so absorbed that the world around you fades, and your attention becomes fully focused on what you feel now.
The more you engage in this relational way, the more you settle into flow, where you and the unfolding moment are not separate, and each sensation draws you deeper into presence.
You don't need to get it right.
Stay with each wave of sensation, allowing yourself to be fully immersed until you are at one with the unfolding moment, fully absorbed, fully attuned, fully present.